好吧，这是第四次讲座，孩子们当然要离开我们了
all right this is a fourth lecture the
kids matter of course where we left off
上一次我们谈论自由电子
last time
we were talking about the free electron
或金属自由电子的Sommerfeld理论金属和
or the Sommerfeld theory of metals free
electron Sommerfeld theory of metals and
Sommerfeld在做什么，他或多或少地遵循了金属设计
what Sommerfeld was doing he's more or
less following drew design that a metal
只是电子的气体，他试图应用动力学理论
is just a gas of electrons and he was
trying to apply kinetic theory the only
他做的不同的事情是他尊重费米的统计数据
thing he was doing differently is he was
respecting Fermi statistics he was
跟踪您不能将两个电子放在一起的事实，我可以这样说：
keeping track of the fact that you can't
put two electrons in one I can state and
在上一堂课中，我们得出了费米波矢与密度相关的信息。
last lecture we derived that the Fermi
wave vector is related to the density of
电子由三个PI平方n到三分之一，其中n是电子
electrons by three PI squared n to the
one third where n is the electron
密度，不幸的是，在上一讲中，我错误地犯了一个错误
density and unfortunately in the last
lecture I made an error I mistakenly
称此为费米动量实际上是费米波矢
call this thing the fermi momentum it's
actually the Fermi wave vector and I
甚至将其错误地写在板上h-bar乘以波矢KF为
even wrote it on the board incorrectly
h-bar times the wave vector K F is the
费米的势头对此感到抱歉
fermi momentum sorry about that
从费米波矢量中，我们可以用通常的方法EF获得费米能量
from the Fermi wave vector we can get
the Fermi energy in the usual way EF is
H bar平方KF平方超过2m，我们可以用以下表达式代替
H bar squared K F squared over 2m which
we can substitute in our expression for
自由波矢量H bar平方2m 3 PI平方n等于2/3这是
the free wave vector H bar squared over
2m 3 PI squared n to the 2/3 this is a
非常重要的关系，我们将再次使用，但重要的是
rather important relationship that we'll
use again but what's important to
意识到这里的电子密度越大，电子越大
realize here is the bigger the density
of electrons you have the bigger the
费米能，在像铁或铅这样的典型金属中，电子的密度为
fermi energy and in a typical metal like
iron or lead the density of electrons is
每个原子真的有几个电子，而你有很多原子
really big a couple of electrons per
atom and you have a whole lot of atoms
原子和原子每两埃的极高密度，所以费米
the very high density of atoms and atom
every couple angstroms so the fermi
能量变得巨大，达到80,000开尔文甚至更高
energy gets to be enormous on the order
of 80,000 Kelvin or even bigger
有时在本讲课中，我们现在打算瞄准
sometimes now in in this lecture what
we're going to aim to
是我们之前讨论的热容量，从实验中我们
is something that we discussed earlier
the heat capacity and from experiment we
知道低温下金属的热容量采用这种形式的t立方
know the heat capacity for metals at low
temperature takes this form of t cubed
加号T，这个T立方项来自振动或德拜理论，我们
plus plus T where this T cubed term
comes from vibrations or Debye theory we
已经讨论过，这个伽马T术语对金属来说是特殊的，实际上是
discussed that already and this gamma T
term is special to metals and in fact is
电子的热容量，所以我们要使用的是伽马T项
the heat capacity of the electrons so
it's this gamma T term that we're going
要对今天感兴趣，在我们实际执行此操作之前，我们需要做一些操作
to be interested in today now before we
actually do this we need to do a little
特别是一些预备代数，我们将需要一些
bit of preparatory algebra in particular
we're going to need to take some over
并将其置于比本征态更可行的形式
eigenstates and put it into a more
workable form than the eigenstates in
这种情况将是e，你知道平面波e到IK点R和
this case are going to be e to the you
know plane waves e to the I K dot R and
再一次，因为我们将其写为指数式就是我们隐式的
again since we're writing this as
exponential is what we're implicitly
我们要做的是将事物放置在Borna von Karman边界框内
doing is we're putting the thing in a
periodic box Borna von Karman boundary
条件在所有方向上都是周期性的，因此我们可以处理指数平面波
conditions periodic in all directions so
we can work with exponential plane waves
而不是正弦和余弦，我们想要做的是
instead of sines and cosines what we'd
like to do is we'd like to take this sum
超过本征态，我们想将其转换成能量的积分
over eigenstates and we would like to
convert it into an integral over energy
能量g，其中g现在是状态密度，这与我们非常相似
g of energy where g is now a density of
states this is very similar to what we
从理论上讲，当我们做了两个时，我们会做些什么？
did when we did two by theory how are we
going to do something slightly different
在这里稍有不同，我们将从
here slightly different we're going to
remove a factor of the volume from the
状态密度，所以现在是每单位体积的状态密度，我们这样做
density of states so this is now density
of states per unit volume and we do this
因为这样做很传统，而且这样做很方便，如果您
because it's conventional to do so and
it's convenient to do so and if you
在传统和方便来自同一个词之前没有注意到它
didn't notice it before conventional and
convenient come from the same word so
这就是所有这些事情，恰好这样做很方便，所以我们
it's it's both of those things it just
happens to be handy to do so so we're
要去做，然后写出这种状态密度的定义是
going to do it and then write the
definition of this density of states is
ede的G是州的数目
that G of e d e is the number of states
在这种情况下，每单位体积的能量在ε和
per unit volume in this case volume with
energies energies between epsilon and
epsilon plus D Epsilon非常类似于我们为Debye所拥有的
epsilon plus D Epsilon
very similar to what we had for Debye
我们以前在思考每个频率的密度状态之前的理论
theory before when we were thinking
about density States per frequency now
总体思路还是要对所有本征态求和
the general idea again is we're going to
take the sum over all the eigenstates
我们实际上将把各个本征态的总和转换为
and we're actually going to convert that
sum over individual eigenstates to an
能量的积分乘以每个能量的状态数
integral over energies times the number
of states at each energy just a
不同的写作方式可以让您的生活更轻松，好吗
different way of writing it that makes
your life a lot easier all right so what
我们要在这里做的事情是从总和算起第一件事
are we going to do here to get from the
sum into the integral well first thing
我们要对本征态做一些运算，实际上是对K求和，但实际上
we're going to do some over eigenstates
is really a sum over K but it actually
前面有2倍的因子，因为每个K自旋电子有两个自旋
has a factor of 2 out front because
there are two spins per K spins electron
可以用相同的波矢旋转或旋转
can be spin up or it can be spin down
with the same wave vector then we're
进行与理论上相同的操作，从而使
going to do the same manipulation we did
with the by theory leave the factor of
前面两个，我们将用2上的整数D 3k替换K上的和
two out front we're going to replace the
sum over K with an integral D 3k over 2
PI立方体，这是将总和转换为积分的方式，我们将得出
PI cubed this is the way sums get
converted into integrals and we'll make
今年替换很多次，K的总和变成了体积乘以
that replacement many times this year a
sum over K becomes a volume times
积分D 3k超过2 PI立方，然后由于我们正在考虑各向同性
integral D 3k over 2 PI cubed and then
since we're thinking about an isotropic
系统可以在三个笛卡尔方向和两个笛卡尔方向上转换积分
system we can convert the integral over
three Cartesian directions and two
球形极坐标，所以我们要V超过2 PI立方，然后有一个
spherical polar coordinates so we've to
V over 2 PI cubed and then we have an
整数0到无穷大4 PI K平方DK，其中4 PI K平方是通常的4
integral 0 to infinity 4 PI K squared DK
where the 4 PI K squared is the usual 4
pi是球面上的方向，所以它是通常的球面极性
pi is the directions on the sphere so
it's the usual spherical polar
坐标，这是一个很好的结果，但实际上我们很想写
coordinates and this is a pretty good
result but really we'd like to write
这是根据能量而不是波矢，因此我们将使用epsilon
this in terms of energies not in terms
of wave vectors so we'll use epsilon is
H bar平方K平方超过2m，否则我可以写成K平方
H bar squared K squared over 2m or I
guess we could write that as K is square
H bar的2m根乘以ε到一半，尤其是
root of 2m over H bar times epsilon to
the one half and in particular that
会给我们DK同样的事实，是相同因子平方的1/2倍
would give us DK is the same fact well
it's 1/2 times the same factor square
H bar上2m的根乘以epsilon到负1/2 D Epsilon，然后如果我们插入
root of 2m over H bar times epsilon to
the minus 1/2 D Epsilon then if we plug
这些东西放到这里，然后我们得到的就可以了，所以我们现在有两个音量
these things into here what we then get
is ok so we now have two volume I'll
拉出4pi，我们在楼下有2个PI立方体，然后有一个
pull out the 4pi and we have the 2 PI
cubed downstairs then we have an
将0积分到无穷大D Epsilon，然后将这些因子放入K中
integral 0 to infinity D Epsilon and
then putting in those factors for the K
平方DK我们得到1/2，其中三个因子2m平方根2m
squared DK we get 1/2 there's three of
these factors 2m square root of 2m over
将H条切成立方体，然后将其ε化为1/2，这看起来几乎就像我们想要的
H bar cubed and then epsilon to the 1/2
so this looks almost like what we want
它几乎是e的G的整数，所以我们确定好吧，所以我只是
it's almost the integral of G of e de so
we then identify well ok so I'll just
再次写出来，所以这个东西对于e de的无穷大G是整数0
write it out again so this thing is
integral 0 to infinity G of e de where
我们已经定义了e的G到D的M到H bar立方时间的三分之二
we've defined G of e to then D to M to
the three-halves over H bar cubed times
2 pi平方中的1乘以epsilon至1/2，因此密度保持与
1 over 2 pi squared times epsilon to the
1/2 so density stays proportional to
epsilon到1/2，这是一个很好的答案，但实际上
epsilon to the 1/2 and this is a
perfectly good answer but it's actually
方便，因此通常可以在H bar上转换2 m的因数
convenient and therefore conventional to
to convert this factor of 2 m over H bar
切成看起来更好的东西，而我们的方法是使用
cubed into something that looks a little
nicer and the way we do that is by using
这个方程在这里，那方程确保如果我把它写在这里
this equation here that equation there
make sure maybe write it over here if I
将该等式带到三等分的幂中，我得到EF的三等分
take that equation to the three halves
power I get EF to the three halves
等于H bar超过2m的立方，等于三分之二乘以3 PI平方
equals H bar cubed over 2m
to the three-halves times 3 PI squared
我做对了吗我想我做对了
and did I do that right I think I do
that right
好的，然后您会注意到我可以解决这个问题
ok and then you'll notice that I can
turn this around
或将其倒置至M到三分之三的h bar的立方，则为3
or make it upside down to M to the
three-halves over h bar cubed is then 3
pi在EF上将n平方为三分之二，这里的系数就是这里的系数
pi squared n over EF to the three-halves
and this factor here is this factor here
所以插入，我们得到e的e的G就是我知道的3 PI平方密度
so plugging that in we get G of e of e
is then what 3 PI squared density I know
这是很多代数，这是重要的代数日，因为这是星期一
this is a lot of algebra it's a big
algebra day because it's a monday
将三分之二的π平方乘以1到二分之一，然后取消一些
three-halves 1 over 2 pi squared epsilon
to the one-half and then canceling a few
我们得到最终结果的结果g epsilon的密度是EF的三分之二
things we get our final result g of
epsilon is three-halves density over EF
倍于EF的能量达到一半，没有犯任何错误，看起来
times energy over EF to the one-half
didn't make any mistakes does that look
正确的任何对象看起来都很好，这将是相当公平的
right anyone object look good all right
this is going to be something fairly
有用的，尤其是查看状态的密度是有用的
useful and in particular it's useful to
look at the density of states at the
费米能量仅是EF的三分之二
Fermi energy which is just three-halves
density over EF which i think is
您被要求从他们的家庭作业中得到的东西以及第一个
something that you're asked to derive in
their homework as well the first
作业，我会给你一个快速提示，我认为这是一种更简单的方法
homework set and I'll give you a quick
hint that I think there's a easier way
比我刚刚做的要去那儿，但你知道如果你不明白
to get there than what I just did but
you know if you can't figure it out you
可以跟随这个，但是有一种更便宜的方法，但是这个是
can just follow this but there's there's
a cheaper way but this one's this is
您知道的越多，路线越直接，另一种方式是
sort of the more you know it's the more
direct route the other way is sort of
无论如何，运动鞋看看现在您是否能以任何速度解决问题，
sneakier anyway see if you can figure it
out ok at any rate now we're going to
尝试使用这个结果找出我们知道状态的密度
try to use this result figure out we
know the density of states here density
说单位体积，我们将尝试使用它来计算热量
say for unit volume we're going to try
to use this to figure out the heat
电子在低温下的容量现在总是超过
capacity of the of the electrons at low
temperature now there's always more than
一种做某事的方法，有正确的方法，有作弊的方法
one way to do something there's the
right way and there's the cheating way
我要做的是我实际上
and
what I'm going to do is I'm actually
将解释如何正确地做，然后我们将作弊，
going to explain how the right way is
done and then we're going to cheat and
我们之所以作弊是因为正确的方法是代数
the reason we're gonna cheat is because
the right way is algebraically really
太可怕了，仅仅通过做代数我们很难获得任何直觉
horrible and it's really hard to get any
intuition just by doing algebra we just
做了足够的代数，我保证你用正确的方法做三遍
did enough algebra and I promise you
doing it the right ways is three times
更重要的是，实际的计算是，我真的
more so furthermore the actual
calculation is so I was really
很复杂，您在牛津大学的任何考试中都不会被问到，那就是我
complicated that you'll never be asked
it on any exam at Oxford and that is I
意思是我不能100％保证它，但我可以99％保证它是这样
mean I can't 100% guarantee it but I can
99% guarantee it so so in that so
因此，我们将采取欺骗手段，使您
because of that we're gonna just do it
the cheating way which gives you the
对正在发生的事情的直觉，避免了很多代数，但这是值得知道的
intuition for what's going on and avoids
a lot of algebra but it's worth knowing
至少如果你真的想诚实的话你会怎么做，如果你
at least how you would go about it if
you really want to be honest so if you
老实说你首先要做的是写一个方程式
really want to be honest what you would
do first is you would write an equation
系统中的电子数，我们之前写了这个方程
for the number of electrons in the
system and we wrote this equation before
上次是所有本征态的总和
last time it's the sum over all
eigenstates of the probability that each
本征态被填充，本征态的概率为
eigenstate is filled and that
probability of an eigenstate being
填充的是β的费米函数，是时间的逆温度乘以能量
filled is the Fermi function of beta the
time inverse temperature times energy of
本征态减去mu的化学势
the eigenstate minus mu the chemical
potential and being that we just derived
状态密度我们可以将其重写为体积乘积
the density of states we can rewrite
that as an integral while volume times
每单位体积乘以状态密度从0到无穷大的整数
the integral from 0 to infinity of the
density of states per unit volume times
Fermi函数，所以它与ε表达式完全相同
a Fermi function so it's exactly the
same the same expression the epsilon
完全相同的表达式，除了在本征态上写和
exactly the same expression except
instead of writing sum over eigenstates
您在所有能量上积分每种能量的状态数和
you integrate over all energies the
number of states at each energy and of
当然，您总是在整合状态被填充的概率为
course you're always integrating the
probability that a state is filled is
每个人都很好，是的，是的，现在很好，您可以想到的这个方程式
everyone good with this yes yeah ok good
now this equation here you can think of
它以两种不同的方式之一是您是否可以修复化学势，
it in two different ways one way is if
you could fix the chemical potential and
你知道温度会告诉你你有多少电子，但是更多
you knew the temperature it would tell
you how many electrons you have but more
通常它会绕着相反方向知道电子数
often than not it goes the other way
around you know the number of electrons
您在系统中拥有的，因为您知道您拥有多少原子或其他什么东西
you have in your system because you know
how many atoms you have or something
这样，您就知道了温度，它使您能够找出
like that and you know the temperature
and it enables you to figure out the
化学势，所以有点像你知道逆关系
chemical potential so it's sort of a you
know an inverse relationship you know
这个你知道这个，所以你可以找出
this
you know this and so you can figure out
原则上来说，这样做虽然在代数上很麻烦，但是
this in principle although it's
algebraically messy to do so but in
原则上，您可以算出化学势
principle it would allow you to figure
out the chemical potential given that
你知道粒子的数量，知道温度后，
you know the number of particles and you
know the temperature once you have the
化学势，您可以为系统中的能量写一个表达式
chemical potential you could write an
expression for the energy in the system
再次积分所有状态的积分，但现在您积分了能量
integral again integrating over all
states but now you integrate the energy
乘以一个状态被填充的概率
times the probability that a state is
filled okay
因此，您不仅要对粒子进行计数，还要对粒子次数进行计数
so instead of just counting the
particles you count the particles times
它们的能量来获取系统中的总能量，以便您找到化学物质
their energy to get the total energy in
the system so you find the chemical
势首先，您一旦知道化学势便找到能量
potential first you then find the energy
once you know the chemical potential
因此，您将知道能量是温度的函数，您可以
then therefore you would know the energy
as a function of temperature you can
因此从这种原理上区分得到热容量
differentiate that to get the heat
capacity so in principle from this kind
从理论上讲，如果您可以进行这些积分，就可以获得热容量
of argument you could get the heat
capacity if you could do these integrals
问题是这些积分是否真的很讨厌，这就是为什么我们不
the problem is if these integrals are
really nasty and that's why we're not
将以这种方式进行，相反，我们将做出一些假设
going to do it this way instead we're
going to make some assumptions which
不太正确，但先看看假设是什么，让我先画一个
aren't quite right but to see what the
assumptions are let me first draw a
再次这是我们上次绘制的F 0的费米函数
diagram this is the Fermi function again
which we drew last time an F 0
温度和F从1到右边，这里F 1到0，所以这是T
temperature and F goes from 1 to right
here the F 1 to 0 so this is this is T
等于0，然后有限e Fermi函数会像
equals 0 and then a finite e the Fermi
function smears out a little bit like
这是T大于0好吧，这一切看起来都很熟悉，我希望好
this is T greater than 0
ok this all looks familiar I hope ok
顺便说一句，我相信这个完整的计算，我认为您实际上已经做到了
incidentally I believe this full
calculation I think you actually did it
去年在您的统计机修课程中，或者至少是讲师，您知道
last year in your stat mech course or at
least lecturer did it and you know you
可能记得那很可怕，很难记住
probably remember that it was pretty
awful and it's hard to actually remember
关于代数真的很糟糕的一切直觉
anything about the intuition of what's
going on if the algebra is really awful
因此，我们将尝试以Chiti方式进行操作，从而为您提供
so we're going to try to do this in the
Chiti way that is going to give you the
直觉好多了，所以我们要假设的一件事是
intuition a lot better so the one thing
we're going to assume which isn't quite
是的，但是非常接近的是，化学势不会
right but it's pretty close to right is
that the chemical potential doesn't
实际上是随温度变化的，现在它确实改变了
actually change as a function of
temperature now it does change the
由于这个快速方程，温度的函数，但它只会改变
function of temperature because of this
quick equation but it only changes a
有点为什么，如果看一看费米，它只会改变得很好
little bit why is it it only changes a
little bit well if you look at the Fermi
您可以想象这里的功能随着温度的升高而发生了什么
function here you can imagine as you
raise the temperature what's happening
这是我们现在填补的一些州
here is some of
the states here that we're filled now
移到这里，所以这里有些电子被清空了
move to here so some there were some
electrons here they empty out and they
现在将这些州填满吧
fill these states up here okay now if
the number of states that empty out and
这个数字说它充满了彼此的化学势
the number says it fills are equal to
each other the chemical potential
完全不需要移动，您可以保持化学物质不变
doesn't have to move at all you would
keep in constant keeping the chemical
实际上，您必须调整化学势a
potential constant now in truth you have
to adjust the chemical potential a
一点点随温度变化的函数，以保持粒子总数
little bit as a function of temperature
to keep the total number of particles
固定，但基本上不必调整很多化学势
fixed but you don't have to adjust it a
lot basically the chemical potential
保持几乎完全相同，所以我们要做出这个假设
stays almost exactly the same so we're
going to make this assumption where do I
写出来，也许这里假设mu的深度与T无关
write it maybe here
assume mu is in depth independent of T
这不是很正确，但是一旦我们有了一个近似值，还算不错
it's not quite right but it's not too
bad an approximation once we have that
好吧，一旦有了，我们可以在这里取这个方程，然后说
well actually once we had that we could
take this equation here and then say
好吧，让我们插入固定的mu作为温度的函数，然后我们
okay let's plug in mu fixed as a
function of temperature and then we
假设mu是固定的，则可以计算能量随温度的变化
could calculate the energy as a function
of temperature here assuming mu is fixed
区分它并获得热容量，但即使那样太复杂
differentiate it and get the heat
capacity but even that's too complicated
因为这个积分真的很讨厌，所以我们甚至都不会这样做
because this integral is just really
nasty so we're not even going to do that
我们将做一些更简单的事情，所以我们要做的是
we're going to do something even simpler
so what we're going to do is we're going
写某个温度T处的能量等于T处的能量等于零
to write the energy at some temperature
T is the energy at T equals zero plus
两个非常近似的事物近似事物之一是电子数量
two very approximate things approximate
thing one is number of electrons that
会变得兴奋，会变得兴奋，而事物2是x的能量
can get excited that can get get excited
and thing 2 is x amount of energy of
能量各自吸收，所以您可以想象从零温度开始，然后
energy each absorbs so you imagine
starting at zero temperature and then
你打开温度，然后一些电子会被激发
you turn on the temperature and then the
some number of electrons can get excited
每个人吸收的能量总量，一些能量和
each one absorbs a total amount of
energy some amount of energy and the
这两个的乘积大致为您提供了您已经拥有的总能量
product of these two roughly gives you
the total amount of energy that you've
通过合理的声音来增加您的系统是的，是的，这是否合理
increased your system by sound
reasonable yeah yes yes is it reasonable
大概是对的，你知道这大概是对的。
it's roughly true you know it's roughly
right okay bear with me okay so now we
我们要做的就是找出这两个因素是什么
all we have to do is we have to figure
out what are these two factors so the
可以激发的电子数，所以这是
number of electrons that can get excited
so this is this is sort of the
有趣的是，被激发的电子数量大致
interesting piece here the number of
electrons that are excited is roughly
在EF y的KBT内的电子数，因此必须在这个范围内
number of electrons within within KBT of
EF y so you have to be so this range
这是关于KBT的信息，您必须在EF的范围内才能获得
here is about KBT and you have to be
within this range of EF in order to get
兴奋，因为如果您在这里更远的地方，您将不会兴奋
excited because if you're farther down
here somewhere you can't get excited
很难兴奋到正确的地步，所以那是你无法得到的
hard to get excited right so it's you
can't get it that was supposed to be
有趣的是，您的电子处于这种状态，我根本无法兴奋，因为
funny you an electron in the state down
here I can't get excited at all because
充满兴奋的所有状态，所以无法移动，它只是卡住了
all the states it would get excited into
re filled so can't move it's just stuck
在那种状态下，除非你把
in that state and it's going to be
frozen there unless you turn the
你知道温度很高，所以它可能一路跳到这里好，所以
temperature you know huge so it could
jump all the way up to here okay so it's
EF的KBT内的电子数量以及它的数量
the number of electrons within KBT of EF
and how many is that well it's basically
费米能量乘以单位体积的状态密度乘以体积
the density of states per unit volume at
the Fermi energy times the volume so
这样就可以得到费米每单位能量的状态总数
this gives you the total number of
states per unit energy at the Fermi
表面乘以KB T，因此我们在此采用每单位体积的状态数
surface times KB T so we're taking the
number of states per unit volume at this
能量，我们将其乘以该范围即可得出
energy and we're multiplying it by this
range to give you the total number of
EF的KBT中的状态让我考虑该因子，然后将其乘以
states within KBT of EF let me take that
factor and we multiply it by the amount
每个电子吸收的能量大约为KBT
of energy each electron absorbs which
has got to be roughly KBT
Gabey G乘以KB T，所以费米的KBT内从这里下来的一些电子
Gabey G times KB T here so some electron
from down here within KBT of the Fermi
通过吸收大约KBT的能量，表面激发到了这里
surface got excited up to here by
absorbing about KBT of energy and then
你知道要尝试对我们
you know to be to try to be a little bit
more honest about the fact that we're
作弊完全作弊在这里，我要添加一个软糖因素，所以
cheating completely cheating here well
I'm going to add a fudge factor so e
t处的e等于0加上我们刚刚得出的因子
total is e at t equals zero plus those
factors they are which we just derived
就是G @ EF乘以KB T的平方
so to be G @ EF times KB T squared and
then the fudge factor is we'll call
伽玛twiddle超过2和伽玛twiddle只是我们承认内
gamma twiddle over 2 and gamma twiddle
is just our admission of guilt that we
并没有进行真正的真实计算，我们知道我们将得到答案
didn't do a real real calculation we and
we know we're going to get the answer
由于阶数为1的某种因素而引起的错误，所以您可能知道伽玛旋转-它
wrong by some factor of order 1
so gamma twiddle could be you know - it
可能是1/2，可能是馅饼，可能是2 pi，但不会是100
could be 1/2 it could be pie it could be
2 pi but it's not going to be a hundred
不会是一千，不会是0.01，所以这是一些
it's not gonna be a thousand it's not
going to be 0.01 okay so it's some
一阶的数字，这是我们承认的内感，而我们没有
number of order one which is our
admission of guilt that we didn't
有了这个表达式，我们就可以真正进行真正的计算了
actually do the real calculation okay
once we have this expression we can of
当然要区分CV de DT，这就是为什么我将2的因数
course differentiate it CV de DT which
is this is why I put the factor of 2 in
因此，当您区分下一个聪明的KB，然后区分EF和G时，它就消失了
so it goes away when you differentiate
next clever the KB and then G at EF and
您剩下KBT，实际上我们已经在那派生了G @ EF，所以
you're left with KBT and in fact we
already derived G @ EF over there so
让我们将其插入三等分和EF，我们还将使用
let's plug it in three halves and over
EF and we're also going to use maybe
我在这里将其作为一种方便的常规
I'll put it here
a convenient conventional that the
密度乘以体积就是粒子数，所以当我乘以
density times the volume is the number
of particles so when I multiply this
很好地在这里写下来，所以我在这里乘以三半并超过EF
factor by well write it out here so I
multiplied three halves and over EF here
用V表示V和较小的端点给您较大的端点，我们将让这个伽玛旋转
by V the V and the small end give you a
big end and we'll get this gamma twiddle
因数乘以三倍大n KB乘以EF的KB T好吧，这就是我们的
factor times three halves big n
KB times KB T over EF okay so that's our
最终结果，实际上如果您真的进行了计算，您会
final result and actually if you did the
calculation really honestly you would
发现伽玛旋转是PI乘以3的平方，我确定你是
discover that gamma twiddle is is PI
squared over three and I'm sure you're
不会为知道这一点而负责，只是为了您知道我们
not going to be held responsible for
knowing that but just for you know our
如果您是普通的教育者，那么数字实际上就是
general edification that's what the
number actually happens to be if you
真的很想看看如何进行此计算您可以返回统计信息
really want to see how to do this
calculation you can go back to your stat
去年的机械笔记，或者您可以知道吗？
mech notes from last year or you can you
know this it's in a lot of a lot of
书本等等，当人们说你知道书本很多时，你知道我讨厌它
books and so forth you know I hate it
when people say you know it's in a lot
书，但请相信我，您知道如果
of books but trust me you know the
algebra doesn't really teach you much if
你真的知道，你想知道它是如何完成的吗
you really you know want to see how it's
done you can you can work through it
Sommerfeld确实通过了这项工作，他得到了正确的答案，但我们没有去
Sommerfeld did work through it he got
the right answer but we were not going
反正你对此负有责任
to be you know held responsible for it
anyway
关于此结果的几个重要事项首先是线性关系
a couple of important things about this
result first of all it's linear in
温度及其温度呈线性的原因基本上来自
temperature and the reason it's linear
in temperature comes fundamentally from
只有费米表面附近的电子才能吸收能量的事实
the fact that only electrons near the
Fermi surface can absorb energy okay
当温度降至零时，可以激发的电子范围接近
when temperature goes to zero the range
of electrons that can get excited near
费米表面降到零，而您的热容量完全消失了
the Fermi surface drops to zero and you
lose your heat capacity altogether okay
所以实际上这是我们想要通过实验获得的热量
so in fact this is what we wanted
experimentally we wanted to get a heat
温度是线性的，这是第一件事
capacity that is linear in temperature
so that's the first good thing about
这个表达真的很好的另一件事是
this another thing that's really nice
about this expression is you'll
在这里认识到这件作品在这件作品中，它是古典作品
recognize this piece here this piece
here as the classical result classical
来自单原子气体的三分之二和kb听起来很熟悉，然后
result from a monatomic gas three-halves
and kb sounds familiar right and then
它乘以这个系数，因此KBT超过EF，这是很小的
it's multiplied by this factor here KBT
over EF which is what it's tiny it's
例如室温300开尔文超过80,000开尔文
like room temperature 300 Kelvin over
80,000 Kelvin tiny tiny tiny amount so
你只有一个事实，那就是只有几个电子
you have only again coming from the fact
that only a few electrons are
参与热容，所以索默费尔德的这一结果过去了，他
participating in the heat capacity so
this result in Sommerfeld went and he
说好的，这是我对费米气体的热容量的新预测
said okay this is my new prediction for
what the heat capacity of a Fermi gas
应该是，所以让我们将其与实验进行比较好吧，让我们写
should be and so let's compare it to
experiment so well okay so let's write
当所有这些常量都被伽玛t吸收时，
it as gamma t all those constants get
absorbed into the overall
伽玛，如果您想知道多少热量的真实理论，他会没事的
gamma and he's going to okay if you if
you want a real theory of how much heat
容量特定的金属应该具有您需要知道的密度
capacity particular metal should have
you need to know what the density of the
金属中的电子是，所以您可以计算EF，但他做了平常的事情
electrons in the metal is so you can
calculate EF but he did the usual thing
说好吧，让我们假设每个原子有一个电子
and said okay let's assume one electron
per atom the same way we've done before
如果这样做，则为实验划分出伽玛C伽玛
and if you do that then you write out
gamma C gamma for the experiment divided
根据理论中的伽马，并且假设每个原子有一个电子
by gamma from the theory and with the
Theory assuming one electron per atom
对于锂，我们得到2.3，对于钠，我们得到1.3钾1.2铜1.5，这是
for lithium we get 2.3 for sodium we get
1.3 potassium 1.2 copper 1.5 this is a
相当不错的协议，考虑到
pretty good agreement it's extremely
good agreement considering that the
古典理论犹大所做的三分之二的nkb结果太大了
classical Theory what Judah had done the
three-halves nkb result is too big by a
因数是100，突然之间我们得到了非常漂亮的结果
factor of 100 and all of a sudden we're
getting results which are really pretty
接近正确答案以及我们获得接近结果的原因
close to the right answer and the reason
we're getting results that are close to
正确的答案是因为现在更诚实地检索费米统计信息还可以
the right answer is because retrieving
Fermi statistics more honestly now okay
好吧，我们之前根本没有对待他们，现在索默菲尔德说你把它放进去
well we didn't treat them at all before
and now Sommerfeld said you put it in
费米统计，你现在就可以得到正确的热容量
the Fermi statistics you get the heat
capacity right okay now he went on and
说，事实上，有了对发生的事情的新发现
said in fact with this newfound
understanding of what's going on
你知道费米统计很重要，我们可以解决一些
you know Fermi statistics being
important we can fix some of the
犹大理论的问题，然后是你回想起犹大的事情之一
problems with judah theory and then one
of the things that you recall from judah
理论上回想犹大，我们计算出的东西之一，实际上使我们变得很漂亮
theory recall judah one of the things we
calculated which we actually got pretty
靠近右边的是导热系数
close to right was the thermal
conductivity thermal conduct the
导热系数密度/每cv热容量
the thermal conductivity one third
density cv heat capacity per per
电子然后是b平方乘以tau散射时间，并在此画出了de
electron then it was b squared times tau
scattering time and drew de in this
犹大（Judah）曾经用过这些表情，这些表情我们不再喜欢
expression judah used used these things
that we don't like anymore the CV is
三分之二kb经典结果，他也将经典结果用于V
three-halves kb the classical result and
he also used the classical result for V
在pi上平方8k BTW KBT，因此组合CV
squared 8k
BTW KBT over pi m so the combination CV
V平方乘以实际进入导热系数的乘积
times V squared which actually enters in
the thermal conductivity it has the
比琥珀色的pi k kb t值高12，现在好了，Sommerfeld说这两个
value 12 over pi c kb t over amber right
okay now Sommerfeld said both of those
结果是错误的，所以让我们使用正确的结果，这样他的结果就是简历
results are wrong so let's use the right
results so his result was CV is while he
PI取3平方，然后将Kb减为经典结果的三等分，然后
has the PI squared over 3 and then 3
halves Kb the classical result and then
KBF超过EF，然后他说ok和V平方不是由
KBT over EF and then he said ok and V
squared is not not given by the
经典动力学理论结果，但应由VF平方给出
classical kinetic theory result but
should instead be given by VF squared
费米速度平方，使事情变得简单一些，我们可以写
the Fermi velocity squared and just make
things a little bit simpler we can write
EF是质量的1/2乘以VF的平方，那么我们得到了一些抵消
EF as 1/2 mass times VF squared put
those together we get some cancellation
再次，如果我们看cv乘以B平方，我们得到pi平方乘以kb t
again if we look at the factor cv times
B squared we get pi squared times kb t
超过m，所以实际上我们发现与Juda的预测相距不远
over m so in fact what we discover it's
not too far from the juda prediction in
事实上Garuda Sommerfeld Sommerfeld是12块PI立方体之类的东西
fact Garuda Sommerfeld Sommerfeld is is
what it's 12 over PI cubed or something
大约是1/2，所以我得到正确的12个结果非常接近相同的结果
about 1/2 so it gets pretty close to the
same result did I get the right 12 are
PI的立方体是的，我想是的，所以您很接近同一个人
PI's cubed yeah I think so so it's
pretty you get pretty close to the same
结果很好，因为我们喜欢导热系数的答案
result which is good because we like the
answer for the thermal conductivity that
我们进入了犹大理论，它满足了Vietminh Franz定律，
we got in judah theory it satisfied this
Vietminh Franz law that was known to
实验性地存在，所以我们不想破坏它，而实际上Sommerfeld
exist experimentally and so we didn't
want to ruin that and in fact Sommerfeld
理论不会毁了它两个错误热容量和速度抵消
theory doesn't ruin it two mistakes the
heat capacity and the velocity cancel
彼此很好，不是很好，但是很漂亮
each other out
exactly well not exactly but pretty
完全接近，但还有其他一些事情
close to exactly but there were other
things that
犹大犯了错，其中之一就是珀尔帖系数珀尔帖
juda got completely wrong one of them
was the Peltier coefficient Peltier
让我们看看什么完全是系数我想我想我已经离开了
which let's see what was totally a
coefficient I think I think I left it
是的，这是珀耳帖系数pi是CV乘以T
over here yeah okay it was a Peltier
coefficient pi is a CV times T over
减去E的三倍，在朱迪思理论中得出的结果是一百倍
three times minus E and in Judith theory
this came out a hundred times too big
或多或少，但现在如果我们插入新的CV值，这是一百倍
more or less but now if we plug in the
new value of CV which is a hundred times
较小的我们突然间变得看起来不错，所以
smaller we're all of a sudden getting
things that start to look right okay so
这很好，所以Sommerfeld对这个结果非常满意，但是
this is this is good so Sommerfeld was
pretty happy with this result but
不幸的是，与我们所有人一样，他提出了一个新问题
unfortunately as with all us with all
things he introduced a new problem
新问题是什么好吧，让我们回过头来记住电导率
what's the new problem well okay let's
go back and remember the conductivity
在m上的平方tau表达式仍然与Sommerfeld中的结果相同
expression n e squared tau over m that's
still the same result in in Sommerfeld
理论给您相同的预测，最好是相同的预测，因为我们
theory give you the same prediction it
better be the same prediction because we
有比例的您知道我们想获得正确的散热比例
have the ratio of you know we wanted to
get the the right ratio of thermal
从电导率到电导率，我们没有改变热
conductivity to electrical conductivity
and we didn't change the thermal
电导率很大，所以最好不要改变电导率
conductivity much so we better not
change the electrical conductivity much
或多或少取决于您知道PI立方体的12倍
either so more or less up to you know
maybe a factor of 12 over PI cubed we
期望电导率应由以下表达式给出
expect that the conductivity should be
given by this expression
也许这个表达是一个值得坚持的表达，我们不知道
probably this expression is a good one
to stick with and we don't we don't know
tau但我们可以测量Sigma来测量Sigma来获取tau
tau but we can measure Sigma measure
this measure Sigma to get tau get this
得到tau然后从tau中我们可以计算出平均自由程lambda均值
get tau and then from tau we can
calculate the mean free path lambda mean
通过散射长度，该长度现在是Sommerfeld理论中的V乘以tau
pass scattering lengths which would be V
times tau now in Sommerfeld theory we
可能用VF乘以tau代替它，因为电子是
would probably replace this with VF
times tau because the the electrons are
以接近VF的速度移动，问题在于VF接近VF
moving around at speeds close to VF and
the problem is that VF is close to the
光速不是很接近，但是是光速的1％
speed of light
well not close to but it's 1% the speed
的光非常快，这意味着平均路径非常长，所以
of light is extremely fast which means
the mean path is extremely long so
lambda太大了，房间有多大
lambda is huge
unreasonably big how big well at room
茶室lambda的茶室温度可以说是一百埃
temperature at tea room at tea room room
lambda can be say a hundred angstroms
听起来可能不大，但在低T时λ可能又是一毫米
may not sound enormous but at low T
lambda can be a millimeter and again
这对您来说听起来可能不算什么，但您必须考虑一下
that may not sound huge to you but you
have to think about how many things the
电子必须经过它才能很好地散射到每埃
electron has to go past before it
scatters well every angstrom there's
另一个原子或每两个埃是电子可以
another atom or every two angstroms is
another atom that the electron could
碰到了这里，它就走了一百个
bump into so here it goes by a hundred
of them here it goes by the million of
他们撞到东西之前，所以撞到什么东西可以
them before it bumps into something so
what can it have bumped into it could
撞到原子核，它可能撞到核心电子
bumped into the nucleus it could have
bumped into the core electrons it could
已经撞到自由电子气中的其他自由电子
have bumped into the other free
electrons in the free electron gas that
跑来跑去，由于某种原因，它并没有撞到任何一个
are running around and for some reason
it doesn't bump into any of them really
真的很奇怪，这是我们要回答的问题
really strange and this is something
that we're not going to answer until
在我们研究固体的能带理论之后，
much later in the term when we study
band theory of solids so for now the
漫长的平均自由路径只是我们必须要解决的难题
unreasonably long mean free path is just
a puzzle that we're going to have to
处理，这使索默费尔德感到困扰，然后困扰了
deal with so this was something that
troubled Sommerfeld back then troubled a
当时有很多人，但是你知道索默菲尔德很勇敢，他决定
lot of people back then but you know
Sommerfeld was brave and he decided what
否则，您知道我们在了解热容量方面做得很好
else you know we did pretty well over
here understanding the heat capacity the
导热系数珀耳帖系数我们还能计算出什么
thermal conductivity Peltier coefficient
what else can we calculate that we might
能够正确无须担心这个特殊的小问题，因此
be able to get right not worrying about
this particular little problem and so
现在，我们将进行一些乱序绕行，并讨论
now we're going to take a little bit of
a out-of-order detour and discuss a
现在有点磁性，所以这周是今年的最后几次讲座
little bit of magnetism now the last
couple lectures of the year so week
七个完全与磁性有关，所以这有点混乱，但是我
seven are entirely about magnetism so
this is a little bit out of order but I
认为它很适合这里，因为它实际上基于完全相同的
think it fits in here well because it
really is based on exactly the same same
我们刚刚经历的业务以及特定类型的
business that we just we just went
through and the particular type of
我们将要研究的磁学是所谓的pauli副磁学
magnetism we're going to study is what's
known as pauli paramagnetism para
现在自由电子的自由电子的磁性Holly当然是你
magnetism of free electrons of
free electrons now Holly of course you
所有人都知道他是排斥原则的人，他也是骄傲的人
all know him he was the exclusion
principle guy he's also proud people
说他是有史以来最傲慢的人，你知道他曾经告诉过他
said he was the most arrogant man who
ever lived you know he used to tell his
学生，他们犯错是可以的
students that it was okay for them to
make a mistake
当然他从来没有犯错，但是对他的学生来说还可以
of course he never made a mistake
himself but it was okay for his students
犯了一个错误，所以他很典型，但是他是一个非常
to make a mistake so he was sorted that
was typical of him but he was a very
伟大的科学家，他实际上在Sommerfeld进行计算之前就进行了计算
great scientist and he actually did this
calculation before Sommerfeld did it did
他的工作如此之多，应该被称为多元论而不是索默菲尔德
his work so a lot of this maybe should
be called poly theory not Sommerfeld
无论如何，顺磁理论是什么，所以一个人做的就是应用一个
theory at any rate paramagnetism what is
that so what one does is one applies a
磁场进入系统，然后测量产生的磁化强度
magnetic field to your system and you
measure the magnetization that comes out
零零零碎的天空上的比例常数就是
the proportionality constant it sky over
mu naught mu naught here is just the
通常常数渗透率渗透率正确拼写
usual constant the permeability
permeability properly spelling this
错误的渗透性是正确的，无论如何都要正确地进行修正
wrong permeability is that right make
this right anyway that's a constant that
显示在您的数据表上，您知道一些基本常数，
shows up on your data sheet you know
some fundamental constants this Chi here
易感性被称为可接受性易感性
is the susceptibility is known as
acceptability susceptibility so this
方程定义了Chi顺磁功率磁势意味着Chi更大
equation defines Chi paramagnetism
power magnetism means Chi is greater
大于零，换句话说，您向物理系统施加了磁场
than zero so in other words you apply a
magnetic field to the physical system
它会在与磁场相同的方向上产生磁化
and it develops a magnetization in the
same direction as the field that you
应用，所以我们要如何解决这个问题，首先要做的是
applied so how are we going to address
this well first thing we have to do is
我们必须为电子写一个哈密顿量，好吧，P平方超过2m
we have to write a Hamiltonian for our
electrons all right P squared over 2m
通常的动力学术语加上电子自旋与磁场的耦合
the usual kinetic term plus a coupling
of the electron spins to a magnetic
场您可能在上学期的原子物理学课程中看到了这一点，因此Sigma
field you may have seen this in the
atomic physics course last term so Sigma
这是Poway自旋算子可能是自旋跳算子
here is the Poway spin operators
probably spin hop operators and it has
重要的是它的特征值是正负1/2 B是磁场mu
这是玻尔磁子玻尔磁子的基本常数是eh bar超过2 M
here is the Bohr Magneton Bohr Magneton
fundamental constant is eh bar over 2 M
从数字上讲，记住该数字在某处很有用
and numerically it's useful to keep in
mind that that number is somewhere
大约每G特斯拉的每G特斯拉的能量G是G因子，对于
around a Tesla per Kelvin per Tesla of
energy G here is the G factor and for
电子G因子通常是自由电子，您在太空中处于G之外
electrons the G factor is typically well
free electron you are out in space the G
因数是2，所以我们只使用2，这将阻止我们
factor is 2 so we're just going to use 2
and that's going to prevent us from
不得不写g和g旋转而感到困惑，因为我们已经在使用g
having to write g and g twiddle and get
confused because we're already using g
用于状态密度，因为它是常规的，因此方便
for density of states because it's
conventional therefore convenient ok
无论如何，如果您在此时，您可能想知道您是否服用了
anyway and if you're at this point you
might be wondering if you took the
相对论课程上学期我为什么写P平方超过200万
relativity course last term why is it
that I wrote P squared over 2m if we
在您可能期望有磁场的地方，应该
have magnetic fields where you might
have expected that instead you should
P加EA平方超过2m，其中a是矢量势
have P plus EA squared over 2m where a
is the vector potential does this look
是的，很熟悉，所以在动能中出现的EA
familiar from yeah ok so the EA that
shows up in the kinetic energy this is
如果将电子排除在外，会使电子弯曲的那一部分
the piece that makes the electrons
curved if you leave it out the electrons
不要弯腰好吧，我们将其遗漏的原因是我们将其遗漏的原因是
don't curve ok we're going to leave it
out the reason we're leaving it out is
首先是双重的，因为很难治疗它实际上是一个相当
well twofold first of all because it's
hard to treat it's actually a rather
复杂的计算来处理多少电子弯曲以及
complicated calculation to deal with how
much the electrons curved and what that
确实对磁化强度有影响，但是将其省略的更好原因是因为
does to the magnetization but the better
reason to leave it out is because the
此EA术语的影响实际上小于
influence of this term this EA term is
actually less than the influence of the
与自旋耦合与自旋耦合实际上比
coupling to the spin the coupling to the
spin is actually more important than the
耦合到电子的实际物理运动，所以我们将要处理
coupling to the actual physical motion
of the electron so we're going to treat
这个学期，如果您真的想知道
this term we're going to throw out this
term ok if you really want to know the
实际上，这个词会做什么，它将使答案改变三分之一。
answer in fact what this term will do is
it will change the answer by a third in
如果把它放进去，另一个会得到相反的结果
the other its own will get if you put
this in it actually has the opposite
结果我们将到达这里，只有三分之一很大，所以它将使
sign as the result we'll get here and
it's only a third is big so it will make
2/3的最终结果最终结果并不重要，我们将忽略
the final result of 2/3 the final result
it's not important we're going to ignore
目前，我们将保持此状态，因此忽略EA术语
this for now we're going to keep this
alright so ignoring the EA term just
保持旋转项在这里，我们拥有的是
keeping the
the spin term here what we have is that
波矢量为K且自旋向上的电子的能量为零
the energy for an electron with wave
vector K and spin up is ek naught plus
mu BB，而能量下降则为零，而mu BB的能量为H
mu B B whereas energy spin down is ek
naught minus mu B B where ek naught is H
bar平方K平方超过2m的自由电子能，所以这个想法是
bar squared K squared over 2m the usual
free electron energy so the idea is that
当您施加磁场时，自旋电子变得更昂贵
when you apply a magnetic field the up
spin electrons become more expensive the
向下旋转的电子变得越来越便宜，所以将会发生什么
down spin electrons become less
expensive and so what's going to happen
是一些向上自旋的电子会翻转过来试图变得向下
is some of the up spin electrons are
going to flip over to try to become down
自旋电子，因为这会降低其能量，但是它们不能全部翻转
spin electrons because that would lower
their energy however they can't all flip
结束，因为许多州已经满员，他们无法翻身
over because a lot of the states are
already filled and they can't flip over
进入已经充满的状态，所以您将获得其中的一些
into states that are already filled so
you're going to get some of them
翻过来，但不是很多，所以我要在这里用光
flipping over but not a lot of them okay
so I'm going to run out of room here
很快，所以让我们从B等于0开始进行整个计算
pretty quickly so let's start with B
equals 0 and do the whole calculation
我们将在T等于0时进行操作，因为T比TF小得多，所以可以
we'll do it at T equals 0 that's ok
because T is much much less than TF so
它非常接近T等于0，如果我们计算了旋转次数
it's pretty close to T equals 0 and if
we calculated the number of spin up
电子或自旋向上的电子密度
electrons or the density of spin up
electrons as the number of spin up
电子除以B处的体积等于0，它应该与
electrons divided by the volume at B
equals 0 it should be the same as the
在这种情况下，自旋下降电子的数量上下波动是对称的，我们
number of spin down electrons ups and
down are symmetric in that case B and we
可以将整数0写入无穷大de，实际上将截止整数
can write that is integral 0 to infinity
de actually will cut off the integral at
如果我们只计算电子的状态，
EF we're going to count only the
electrons that are the states that are
将e的G填满2，然后将其除以2，因为在这里
filled G of e over 2 and it's I put in
the divided by 2 because here we're
仅针对旋转上升或下降而不是两者都编写表达式
writing expression for only the spin ups
or the spin downs not both of them
e的状态密度G是我们计算的状态密度
G of e the density of states that we
calculated was the total density of
旋转和旋转的状态都可以，所以让我们
states of both spin ups and spin downs
okay so let's
让我们在这里画出自旋运算的e的状态密度G这里是e，你会
let's draw here density of states G of e
for spin ops here this is e and you'll
回想一下董事会上的某个地方，我想我已经将其向下滚动到顶部了，也许是
recall somewhere on the board I think I
scrolled it off the top well maybe it's
是的，这里是E的G与e成正比
over here yeah here it is
the G of E is proportional to e to the
一半，所以这东西看起来像抛物线，然后我们也可以
one-half so this thing looks like a
parabola that way and then we can also
画出e的G代表下降，
plot G of e for the spin downs it's
going to look exactly the same for the
这样旋转下来，它们都充满了费米能量EF
spin downs like this and they both get
filled up to the Fermi energy EF this
是不是零磁场现在添加磁场的方式
isn't zero magnetic field yes
now when we add the magnetic field way
在那里，旋转的电子将变得更加昂贵，这些家伙
up there the spin up electrons are going
to become more expensive these guys are
会被mu BB的能量上移，并且向下旋转的电子是
going to get shifted up in energy by mu
B B and the spin down electrons are
会变得更便宜，所以您将能源消耗降低了
going to become less expensive so you're
going to get shifted down in energy by
mu BB实际上也许我应该在这里删除一些内容，以便一些旋转
mu B B actually maybe I should erased
some things here so some of the spin ups
将要变得翻身成为spin downs以降低
are going to get going to want to turn
over to become spin downs to lower the
能量，让我们来画一下发生了什么，所以一旦添加
energy so let's let's draw that what
happens do this so once we add so this
是因为B在这张图片中等于零B在这里等于零，让我们尝试绘制
is for B equals zero in this picture B
equals zero over here let's try to draw
B在这里不等于零，所以这里我们有能量这里我们有g用于自旋
B not equal to zero over here so here we
have energy here we have g for the spin
E的上升，这里我们有E的下降的G，发生的是
ups of E and here we have G for the spin
downs of E and what happens is that
这些家伙的能量像这样被移动了，这个距离是亩B倍B
these guys got shifted up in energy like
this this distance here is mu B times B
这些家伙被这部如此多的电影所震撼了，好吧，然后我们
and these guys got shifted down this by
this much movie be okay and then we fill
它们都由EF决定，这里是EF，这是EF，因此您会看到一些
them both up to EF here this is EF this
is EF so you see that that some of the
那些旋转起来的家伙在这里清空，并在这里填充这些状态
ones that were spin up these guys here
emptied out and fill these states here
清楚这是怎么发生的，所以这里的这些状态被推高了
is that clear how that happened
so these states here got pushed up in
费米表面以上的能量，所以它们清空了，而这些状态在这里
energy above the Fermi surface so they
emptied out whereas these states here
精力充沛，所以他们充满了好吗
got pulled down in energy so they filled
up okay
是不是很清楚我知道这让我有点困惑
is that clear I know this this gets a
little bit confusing bear with me
因此，如果我们要为自旋密度写一个表达式，我们可以写
so if we want to write an expression for
the spin up density we can write
从零到EF减去mu BB的整数，因为实际上我们只想
integral from zero to EF minus mu B B
because actually we only want to
整合到此处，因为在仅查找此区域时，此处没有此区域
integrate up to here because in finding
only this region not this region here
因为一旦我们加了磁场，这里就只有这个区域
because once we add magnetic field it's
only this region here it's only the
这些人已经被清空了
smaller region here that's filled up
these guys have now emptied de of G of e
我猜超过两个，而下降的次数是从零到EF的整数倍
I guess over two whereas the number of
spin downs is integral from zero to EF
再加上两个以上的g bb de g，因为我们要一直整合到
plus mu b b de g of e over two because
we want to integrate all the way up to
在这里，既然那些人的精力都下降了
here since those have been pulled down
in energy is that clear
好了，所以我们快到了，所以现在我要计算的是n
alright so we're almost there so now
what I want is I want to calculate n
down减去n up，它是EF减去mu B到EF加mu BB的整数倍
down minus n up which is integral de
from EF minus mu B be to EF plus mu B B
EE的G超过2，那么我们就可以了
of G of EE over 2 and then we can just
since this is over over only a little
一小部分能量，我们可以使用矩形规则来计算
small sliver of energy we can use the
rectangular rule to calculate that
积分，我们得到1/2 G的EF x-mu BB um如果需要的话，取消二
integral and we get 1/2 G of EF x - mu
BB um cancel the twos if we want ok
让我们写出EF的G乘以mu B是B然后
let's write out G of EF times mu B is B
and then
最后，我们要寻找的磁化强度是
finally the magnetization which is what
we're looking for the magnetization is
Mubi每个电子的磁化强度为1，磁矩为1
Mubi each electron has a magnetization
of one it has a magnetic moment of one
Bohr Magneton，然后我们得到了旋转下降的密度减去密度
Bohr Magneton and then we have the
density of spin downs minus the density
旋转会给您磁化强度，如果您想知道
of spin ups will give you the
magnetization and if you want to know
为什么以这种方式出现标志，为什么它跌宕-起伏不是起伏-跌倒是因为
why the sign comes out this way why it's
downs - ups not ups - downs it's because
电子上的电荷为负，表示电子自旋
the charge on the electron is negative
meaning the spin of the electron
实际上与它的磁化相反，这很令人困惑
actually points opposite its
magnetization which is pretty confusing
但这是我们必须处理的，因为电子的符号是
but that's what we have to deal with
because the sign of the electron is is
否定，所以我们要插上电源-n向下插
negative
okay so we'll plug in and up - n down so
我们将得到G ef mu b乘以磁场的平方，然后将其称为
we'll get G e f mu b squared times the
magnetic field and you would call the
在磁场而非磁场下磁化率chi的定义，因此我们确定
definition of susceptibility chi over mu
not magnetic field so we identify the
保利功率磁化率是μB平方μn
susceptibility the Pauli power magnetic
susceptibility is mu B squared mu naught
G TF，这又是我们的最终结果，我们可以将其与
G a TF and that's our final result again
we can take this result compared it to
理论胜于Chi的实验，并且可以做各种不同的事情
the theory Theory over Chi experiment
and do it for various different things
锂的比例约为2.5钠的比例为1.8钾的比例为1.6
for lithium that ratio is about 2.5 for
sodium is 1.8 for potassium is 1.6 which
如果我们正在考虑经典粒子，那么这是一个很好的协议
is pretty good agreement now if we were
thinking about classical particles
古典单原子气体然后实际上当您施加磁场时
classical monatomic gas then in fact
when you apply to magnetic field nothing
会阻止他们全部翻身他们会直接进入你的身边
would stop them all from flipping over
they would just go right into there you
知道翻转状态，因为那将是较低的能量，并且是唯一
know the the flip down state because
that would be lower energy and the only
之所以不能全部翻身是因为费米的统计费米
reason they don't all flip over is
because of Fermi statistics Fermi
统计数据阻止它们全部翻转，因为某些状态
statistics prevents them all from
flipping over because some of the states
已经充满了，因此您具有有限的磁化率，而经典
already filled and so you get a finite
susceptibility whereas the classical
计算将预测出无限的敏感性，所以这是
calculation would would predict an
infinite susceptibility so this is
非常好，我们在两到三倍的范围内就收到了结果
pretty good we're getting results there
you know within a factor of two or three
实际的实验，所以这或多或少是我们不得不说的
of the actual experiments so this is a
more or less all we have to say about
Sommerfeld理论，让我们总结几件成功的事
Sommerfeld theory so let's summarize a
couple things successes
自由电子理论理论的成功，这意味着德鲁德再加上
successes of free electron free electron
theory theory which means Drude up plus
Sommerfeld Garuda和Sommerfeld嗯，好吧，我们取得了一些成功
Sommerfeld Garuda plus Sommerfeld um
well okay a couple successes we got the
正确的热容量我们得到了良好的导热性
heat capacity right we got the
conductivity good the thermal
电导率好这两者之比都很好帕尔贴系数在
conductivity good the ratio of those two
are good the Peltier coefficient is in
正确的球场易感性，实际上还有许多其他
the right ballpark the susceptibility
and there's actually many many other
你可以计算出你会得到正确的东西，所以自由电子
things that you can calculate that
you'll get right so the free electron
图片实际上还不错，但是仍然存在一些问题
picture is actually pretty good however
there are still some problems that we're
必须要处理的是，正如我在本讲座前面提到的
going to have to deal with one is that
as I mentioned earlier in this lecture
lambda似乎太大太大了，这是一个大问题，因为
lambda seems too big too big that's a
big problem having a mean free path of a
毫米，这似乎完全不合理，因为我们使用了
millimeter it just seems completely
unreasonable we used that the density of
电子应该是每个原子一个电子，我们有一些直觉，为什么我们
electrons should be one electron per
atom and we had some intuition why we
应该这样做，因为好吧，你知道有一堆电子
should do that because well you know
there's a bunch of the electrons are
束缚在核心轨道上，也许他们不算他们没有绕着他们跑
bound in core orbitals and maybe they
didn't count they don't run around they
只是保持固定不动，但还有其他一些你知道有效的原子
just stay stay fixed but there's some
other atoms you know that works
钠和钾都很好，但是碳呢
perfectly well for sodium and for
potassium but what about for carbon
碳使钻石在价态轨道上具有四个电子，如果
carbon makes Diamond it has four
electrons in its valence orbitals if
在最外层的外壳中有四个电子，实际上它是一个绝缘体
four electrons in its outermost shell
and in fact it's an insulator there are
没有电子自由运行，为什么不在那里发生什么，为什么我们
no electrons running around free so why
not what's going on there why do we
每个原子计数一个电子为什么你根本不计算一些电子
count one electron per atom why do you
not count some electrons at all so what
那些其他电子发生了什么，霍尔效应符号的符号呢
happened to those other electrons what
about the sign of the Hall effect sign
Rh我们的霍尔的霍尔系数总是应该具有相同的符号
of Rh our Hall the hall coefficient it's
always supposed to have the same sign in
在索默费尔德理论中，犹大理论也总是被认为具有相同的符号，我们
Judah theory also in Sommerfeld theories
always supposed to the same sign and we
实验测量了我们没有测量的东西，但是它被测量了
measured experimentally what we didn't
measure but it was measured
从实验上看，实际上迹象出了错，有时又是另一回事
experimentally that in fact the sign
comes out wrong sometimes another thing
我没提到光学特性之前就很有趣
that's kind of interesting I didn't
mention before optical properties are
不同或者也许为什么不同为什么不同
different or maybe why different why
different
我的意思是，不同的金属看起来不同，所以您知道黄金
what I mean by this is that different
metals look different so you know gold
看起来有点像金色的银色看起来有点像银色的铜
looks kind of goldish silver looks kind
of silverish copper look kind of
铜色，因此您知道这个名字，但锡看起来有点像您所知道的
copperish hence the name you know but
tin looks kind of you know lighter and
酵素看起来更暗，它们看起来不同，它们具有不同的光学效果
leaven looks kind of darker they look
differently they have different optical
它们反射不同颜色的特性为什么在自由电子理论中
properties they reflect different colors
why is that in the free electron Theory
他们都应该看起来完全一样我们没有提到的另一件事是
they should all look exactly the same
another thing we didn't address is
磁性磁性，例如铁，
magnetism magnetism um
particular things like iron are
铁磁性来自铁的名称，您可能会磁化
ferromagnetic coming from the name for
iron that you could have magnetization
即使B等于零，也不等于零，您可能在
not equal to zero even when even when B
equals zero you probably studied this in
你的电磁过程为什么自由电子图永远不会得到
your electromagnetism course why is that
free electron picture would never get
最后，库仑相互作用如何？
that finally what about Coulomb
interactions Coulomb interactions when
我们考虑到电子在固体中运转，你知道他们
we think about the electrons running
around in a solid you know that they
有巨大的费米能量，你知道八万开尔文，但是如果你考虑一下
have a huge Fermi energy you know eighty
thousand Kelvin but if you think about
库仑相互作用的能量规模也一样大
the the energy scale of the Coulomb
interaction it's just as big the
电子与原子核的相互作用也接近八十
interaction of the electron with the
nucleus nuclei close by also eighty
千开尔文也有大量的电子与其他相互作用
thousand Kelvin also a huge number the
interaction of the electron with other
通过它运行的电子也有八万开尔文，我们把它扔掉了
electrons that are running by it also
eighty thousand Kelvin we threw it out
完全我们只是将这些电子当作自由气体对待
completely we just treated these
electrons as if there are a free gas no
相互作用，我们只将它们具有费米统计量的事实视为
interactions whatsoever we only treated
the fact they have Fermi statistics to a
在很大程度上，所有这些问题都来自我们同一件事
large extent all of these problems come
from the same thing that we're
一遍又一遍地忽略同一件事，我们将不得不
neglecting the same thing over and over
and over again and we're going to have
更认真地对待一个特定的项目，而那个特定的项目是
to take more seriously one particular
item and that one particular item is
材料具有微观结构详细的微观
that materials have microscopic
structures detailed microscopic
结构原子通常以特定方式以特定方式粘在一起
structures atoms are stuck together in a
particular way frequently a particular
周期性的方式，完全改变了属性，这就是我们
periodic way and that completely changes
that properties and that's what we're
剩下的大部分时间都需要处理
going to have to deal with for much of
the remainder of the term all of these
一旦我们诚实地处理了这一事实，大部分事情都会得到解决。
things to a large extent will be sorted
out once we deal honestly with the fact
原子以某种特定方式排列首先，我们是
that the atoms are arranged in some
particular way the first thing we're
要做的是，我们必须了解为什么这是
going to have to do is we're going to
have to understand why it is that the
原子实际上粘在一起开始，所以开始下一个
atoms actually stick together to begin
with and so starting the next
所以我们将讨论一些化学和化学键
so we're going to discuss a bit of
chemistry and chemical bonding just a
真的很快，多少人有化学反应哦，这很好
really quick thing how many people had a
level chemistry oh that's pretty good
有多少人不好，你是幸运者，因为你不得不
how many did not okay you're the lucky
ones because you're gonna have to
取消学习很多您可能不知道的事情，
unlearn a lot of the things that you
know maybe not like it's always good to
学习学习甚至化学的东西，但是您可能不得不学一些
learn learn things even chemistry but
but you may have to unlearn some of the
您之前学到的东西，因为我们将从一个
things that you learned previously
because we're going to look at it from a
更多的物理观点，我将在星期四，星期四，星期四见
more physics perspective and I will see
you Thursday Thursday Thursday
好，星期四[鼓掌]
okay Thursday
[Applause]